

FARREL SATYA PUTRA MAHENDRA

BATAM, INDONESIA M.FARRELSATYAPUTRA@GMAIL.COM 08117043004

EDUCATION HISTORY UNIVERSITAS BRAWIJAYA

Bachelor

Electrical Engineering Major | 2017 - 2021 GPA - 3.86 (Cumlaude)

INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI BANDUNG

Informatics Major | 2022 - Present Master

WORK EXPERIENCES

R&D SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Labtech International, Ltd | August 2021 - August 2022

- Served as a junior engineer in the SPD (Software Product Development)
 division responsible for the creation of software that describes the related
 products.
- Design user interfaces and create 3D models animation inside the software made for both PC and Android.
- Responsible for the code and program inside the application from the functional affairs of the user interface, animation movements, communication with trainers, and other features that exist in the software.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (Internship)

PT. Aksara Digital Indonesia | Apr 2021 - July 2021

- Maintain a web-based application (front-end and back-end) that can make doctors review patient's medical records easier with Javascript as the main programming language.
- Integrate a business application software called Odoo that has various management functions such as managing registered employees, arranging payments, arranging doctor's remuneration, and etc.

R&D DATA ACQUISITION ENGINEER (Internship)

Labtech International, Ltd | Aug 2020 - Oct 2020

- Design electrical circuits for ongoing products using Eagle.
- Make an interface for the Hybrid Simulator Panel on Sectioned Toyota Prius Project using Unity and Arduino.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCES

COMPUTER VISION PROGRAMMER

Brawijaya Robotics Team | Sep 2018 - July 2021

- Responsible of three soccer robots' (two strikers and one keeper) vision and communication
- 5th Place in "Kontes Robot Indonesia 2020 (KRSBI Beroda)" National Online
- 4th Place in "Kontes Robot Indonesia 2019 (KRSBI Beroda)" Region IV in Mataram

CONTROL SYSTEM LABORATORY ASSISTANT

Universitas Brawijaya | Sep 2018 - July 2021

- Do research and projects in the field of automation and control systems such as PLC and DCS
- · Teach practicums and maintain laboratory equipments

PERSONAL PROFILE

A fresh graduate of Electrical Engineering Brawijaya University. Experienced in programming as proven by contribution to being a robot programmer for three years and several internship experiences. Have an interest and passion in the field of research and development that enhances the ability to face various obstacles and become the best.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Microcontrollers
- Computer Vision
- · GUI making
- Web Development
- Io1
- Control Systems

TECHNICAL SKILLS LANGUAGES

- C, C++, and C#
- · HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Python

SOFTWARE

- · Microsoft Office
- Arduino
- OpenCV
- Qt
- Unity 3D
- MATLAB & Simulink
- EAGLE

CERTIFICATES

• TOEFL ITP

Score: 603

 MICROSOFT OFFICE DESKTOP APPLICATIONS

Score: 91.11%